Hello everyone, today we are talking about the
best
health insurance plan of ICICI Lombard Health Insurance, Elevate
Plan.
Unlimited times bonus feature, maternity
waiting
period, a feature that can be reduced to one year.
Elevate Plan is a plan with many features. To
know all the details of this plan,
watch the video till the end. If this is your first time watching this channel, let me
introduce myself. My name is Binoy. I have been
working in the field of insurance investment and banking for the last 20 years.
First of all, let's look at the profile of this company and its
matrix.
This company is a joint venture between
ICC Bank and Canada-based
Fairfax Holdings. Its joint venture
has years of experience in general insurance business. In India, it specializes in
motor health and fire insurance. If
you look at ICICI Lombard's claim seta ratio health insurance,  The claim
settlement ratio is 90%, the
incurred claim ratio is around 83%, the
compliance ratio is 8.9 out of
10 claims, which is a very competitive
compliance ratio.
Then there is the 11000 plus hospital
network of ICICI Bank Health
Insurance Company all over India. If we
look at the Elevate plan, its basic conditions are that the
minimum age entry is 1 year, there is
no maximum age entry. We can take care of any age. There is
life-long renewability in the
plan. Children can
stay in this plan from 91 days to 30 years. If
we
look at the policy term, we can take a policy for one year, two years,
three years, four years, or five years.
Discounts are available if you take out a five-year policy together.
Multi-year discounts are available after taking four years out of five.
We can select a problem ranging from Rs. 5 lakh to Rs. 30 crore.
Two adults and three children are
admissible in a family floater plan
.
If we look at the core features of the plan, a single AC private
room is inbuilt as a basic feature in this plan
.  There is no co-payment.  That means the
full amount will be settled from our hands
.  There is no copayment, just put the amount in our hands
.  Sublimits There are no
sublimits by disease.
Pre and post hospitalization,
that is, 90 days before admission and
150 days after discharge,
we can claim reimbursement for bills.
Domiciliary treatment is covered. If the
patient
cannot be taken to the hospital or there is no room in the hospital, the
treatment can be done at home and if
there is a doctor's letter, it
can be claimed as a Namukt. Ayush
treatment, Ayurveda, Unani, Homeopathy,
100% covered,
we get the amount reimbursed.  The bonus will
increase by 20% to 100%.  This is
inbuilt.  Now, if we
want the bonus to have
unlimited time, as I mentioned earlier, we
should take it as an add-on.  The basic
inbuilt is 20% plus 100%, which is the basic.
Unlimited restoration is built into the
plan. These are the basic
core features.  If you like this video, please
hit the like button.  The
waiting periods of this plan are: Initial
waiting period is 30 days, 30 days for
accidents only, 31 days for
hospitalization,
specific waiting period
i.e. kidney stone, gall bladder stone,
sinusitis, etc. There is a one-year
waiting period for 18 diseases,
as well as a three-year waiting period for pre-existing diseases.
Stand-alone bill in features One of the features that makes this
plan different is that you can claim up to Rs
5 lakh for
surrogacy and surrogacy. We have
inbuilt features in this plan.
Similarly, nursing at home is available for
Rs 2000 for a few days after the patient is
discharged and reaches home.
Nursing at home is also inbuilt in this plan.
Benefit 30% If we download the ICA Lobad app and
do an activity like walking, the option to reduce the new premium by up to 30% is
available in this plan. The
biggest feature of the plan is that it has 29 add-ons, and there
are many add-ons in it.
There are many add-ons.  That means it's not built-in,
we have to select and add add-ons
.  Similarly, if
we want to reduce the PD waiting period, we can add an
add-on to reduce it to three years. As I said earlier, there is an add-on to reduce it to two years and one year. There is a claim protect add-
on. If we want to get 100% coverage, we can opt out of consumables and so on. We should take the claim protector rider add-on as an add-on. The power
booster increases the bonus by 100%. This is
an add-on that we should take anyway. That is, if we
take a policy of 10 lakhs,
we will get 10 lakhs more every year. That is, if we
take it now, it will be one crore by the end of 10 years, and
two crore by the end of 20 years. So, the
most important thing in health insurance is that it
covers the sub-system, that is, if we say one
and a half crores of coverage by the end of 20 years,
there is a coverage that has been activated. So, when
everyone
takes Elevate, everyone should pay
attention to adding this add-on called power booster. Similarly, the room
modifier  We can bring it to the Any Room Modifier. The
private AC is the one that is included. We can
bring it to the Any Room. There
is a jump start benefit, which means that for
diseases like diabetes and hypertension, we can take the jump start benefit that
covers us on the 31st day itself, without a waiting period.
We can take it as an add-on.
There is an add-on benefit that can reduce the metal waiting period to one year.  Please note that all of this is an add-on
.  It's not inbuilt, we have to
get it as an add-on.
We can get worldwide cover as an add-on.
Similarly, we can take the Critical Illus Cover Rider
as an add-on.
These are all, there are still a few riders left. If you
WhatsApp me,
I will give you more details.  If
you like the video, please
press the like button.  The discounts in the plan are
NR discount of
25%, that is, if a husband is abroad and the
family is in the country, then there is a NR discount of
25%, and there is a
multi-year discount of up to 15%. We said that we can take three years, four years, five years, etc. In that case, there is a multi-discount of
15%. This is the only discount seen in this plan. Credit score discount. If you have a good civil score, there
is an option to take a discount of up to 15% in this plan. Early renewal. If
we take the plan and
renew the next year in advance, a month or
two months in advance,
we have a two and a half percent
discount available.  If you want
to know the premiums of this plan, you
can WhatsApp me on this number.
We have conducted
an updated review of the ICC Lobad Elevate Plan for 2025
.  I like the review
.  If you like it, you should like it anyway
.  If you want to purchase this plan or
know more details about the plan, you
can WhatsApp me.
I can also WhatsApp to compare and purchase the best health insurance.
You can call me at the number you see here.  If you haven't
subscribed to this channel yet, please
subscribe.  So, bye
everyone, until the next video
.